快看 老妈
Hey, mom...
听听老爸给外公的生日卡片上写了什么
Listen to this card dad got for grandpa Jay.
"嘿 嘿 嘿 万岁"
"Hip-hip-hip-hooray!"
多送你一个屁股
"Save the extra hip.
哪天你要装人工肛门时用得着呢
You'll need it someday."
因为他是老人
'Cause he's old!
不准你们送这卡片
You're not giving him that.
-等他酒过三巡再给就行了吧 -还是不行
- If he drinks his other gift first? -Nope.
女孩们
Ladies...
还记得一年前的今天
Do you remember exactly one year ago today
外公得知你们没有给他准备礼物时
when you did not have a gift for your grandfather
他伤心欲绝的样子吗
and it killed him just a little?
我建议你们赶紧去找大伙
So I suggested you start interviewing
录些祝福小短片吧
all the members of the family for a video tribute?
早做好了 管家婆
Well, check it and burn -- we totally did that.
是快做好了
Almost.
只需再稍加剪辑即可
We just need to finish the editing.
你还好意思说呢
And you should talk.
你自己都还没准备礼物
You haven't even started on your gift yet.
因为我改变心意了
That's because I changed mine.
我昨天想到一个更好的主意
I thought of a better idea yesterday.
那主意是我想到的吧
I think I came up with a better idea.
别闹了 我爸爸有一张
Okay. My dad has a picture
我和米奇尔小时候
of me and Mitchell when we were kids,
站在我们老家院子里的照片
standing in our old backyard.
我们准备重现当时的场景
We're gonna re-create the picture.
我去年圣诞节的时候也为我父母做了这事
I did the same thing last year for my parents for Christmas,
反响很强烈 效果很成功
and it went over like gangbusters.
-的确很有趣 -你还记得吗
- Mm. Funny. - Do you remember?
当然记得
Oh, I do. I do.
死也忘不了
I do.
快点 女孩们 关掉电视
Come on, girls, TV off.
今天是你们外公的生日
It's your grandfather's birthday.
我们必须严正以待
We got to start taking this seriously.
请尊许我上船
Permission to come aboard.
我最难忘的生日回忆...
My best birthday memory--
那年我还年少 在我生日那天
I'm a teenager, and for some reason,
我无来由地就自己驾船游湖
I drag this boat out on the lake.
在湖中休息 钓鱼
and for hours, I'm just lying there, fishing,
独自静心思考
alone with my thoughts.
无与伦比的美妙啊
Fantastic.
今年我也只想要这样
That's all I want this year.
你真的想就如此度过这特别的日子吗
So that's really going to be your day?
就这么去钓鱼
You're going fishing?
还够时间去吃吃美食呢
With time out for a gourmet lunch.
香肠俱乐部的五月月度香肠超正点啊
Sausage of the month club really nailed it in may.
亲爱的 你别生气啊
But, honey, no offense.
上个月的西班牙香肠
They almost lost me last month
差点害我再也不想回去了
with that chorizo.
干嘛叫我别生气
Why "no offense"?
只是香肠而已 又没有印在我们国旗上
It's a sausage. It's not on our flag.
莉莉 你在这干吗
Lily, what are you doing here?
惊喜哦
Surprise!
我们要去拿给杰订的蛋糕
We were just on our way to get Jay's cake
就顺路过来拜访一下
and thought we'd pop by.
莉莉今早快把我逼疯了
Lily was driving me crazy all morning.
我得摆脱她这烫手山芋
I had to get rid of her.
她不想穿衣服
She refuses to get dressed.
试过拿东西"贿赂"她了吗
Well, did you try bribing her?
没有...
Oh, no.
才怪呢 早试了
Of -- of course I did!
我不想去哄她了 米奇尔
I cannot go back in there, Mitchell.
当初我们怎么会决定要小孩的啊
Why did we ever decide to have a kid?!
我不知道
I don't know.
我真的不知道
I don't know!
别哭了
Oh, come on!
她太爱你了
She loves you so much.
今天早上 她就盯着你的照片
Just this morning, she was looking at a picture of you,
我发誓 她当时在试着叫你的名字呢
and I swear she was trying to say your name.
真的吗
Really?
我也很想多陪陪她
Ay, I would love to spend more time with her,
可我得去商场给杰买生日礼物
bt I have to go to the mall to get Jay's gift for his birthday.
抱歉 小甜心 歌洛莉亚很忙 没空
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie. Gloria's busy.
别哭了
No, don't cry.
我们还是走吧
We should go.
好吧 其实我也可以带着她...
Oh, maybe I can take her wi--
好的 东西都打包好了 玩的开心点
Okay. Bag's packed. Have fun.
再见了 小甜心
Bye, sweetie.
-你好啊 小卡 -你好啊 曼尼
- Hey, Cam. - Oh, hey, Manny.
妈妈 杰还在吗
Mom, is Jay still here?
-不在 他刚走 -糟糕
- No, he just left. - Shoot.
怎么了 老兄
Why? What's up, pal?
我要去我一个朋友家玩
I'm going over to a friend's house
我可能得知道怎么用这手套
Where I may have to use this thing.
我只用过一次
I only used it once,
而且还是用来拿烤箱里的蛋糕
and that was to take a torte out of the oven.
首先呢 我们得把手套弄软弄松
Okay, well, first, let's loosen this thing up.
-她叫什么名字呢 -你怎么知道是女的
- So what's her name? - How'd you know?
男生打肿脸充胖子
Well, you're pretending to be something you're not.
通常都是为了讨梦中情人欢心 或者梦中情郎
Boys do that for girls... or really dreamy boys.
她叫塔拉 我们在网上聊得很欢
Her name's Tara. We have great chats online.
她德艺双馨 聪明伶俐
She's really smart and funny,
可是她打垒球
but she's on the softball team.
没关系 不可能有完美伴侣的嘛
Well, nobody's perfect.
这样吧
Hey, you know what?
我们出去练几球如何
Why don't we go outside and toss the ball around?
好的
Okay.
而且 你也不需要太杞人忧天
And you know what? I wouldn't worry too much.
就算运动不是你强项 她还是会喜欢你的
She's gonna like you even if sports aren't your thing.
何止不是强项啊
Aren't my thing?
我在楼上有一副网球拍
I have a tennis racket upstairs
我只用来给泡泡浴增加泡泡
I only use as a bubble-bath frother.
这手套怎么戴啊
How do you put this on?
-小姐 借过 -抱歉
- Excuse me, Miss. - Sorry.
叫你小姐也应声
You answered to "Miss"!
真好笑啊
Aha! Hilarious.
格伦·惠普尔 我大学时期的宿敌
Glen Whipple, my college rival --
拉拉队的领导
Captain of Cheer Squad.
机器人大战界的独孤求败
Won every robot battle.
和他在一起时的每分每秒
Every second I spent with the guy
都让我感觉自己好渺小
just made me feel worse about myself.
我唯一可以与他一较高下
The only thing I could compete with him in
就是近景魔术
was close-up magic.
很高兴见到你啊
Well, it's great to see you.
我也是
Great to see you, too.
我想这是你的吧
And I believe this is yours.
怎么可能 什么时候拿的
What? When?
你要去卡片店买卡片吗
Hey, you headed over to the card shop?
我刚刚才去完呢
I was in there earlier.
买了一张音乐贺卡
I got myself one of those musical cards.
虽然有点贵 不过哥还是花的起啦
Oh. They're a little more expensive, but I can swing it.
很好啊 见到你真好
Oh. Well, great to see you. Yeah.
顺便说下 别忘了收好你头后
By the way, don't leave without this quarter
这两角五分钱 加点油啊 菲尔
from behind your -- come on, Phil!
祝你好运 邓菲
Good luck, Dunphy.
我要去买些新的全功能运动鞋
I'm off to get some new cross-trainers.
我的鞋磨损都挺快的
I blow through them pretty fast
因为我很喜欢大步竞走
with all this power-walking I'm into.
回头见
Catch you later.
菲尔
Phil?
你们俩在这做什么
What are you two doing here?
为今晚准备点东西
Shopping for tonight.
好吧 我陪你一起
Oh, well, I'll walk with you.
-你刚去哪里了 -卡片店
- Where were you heading? - The card store.
好可爱的孩子啊
What a beautiful child!
你们夫妻真幸福
You and your wife must be so happy.
我没有多想什么
I didn't think anything of it...
直到别人也都开始犯同样的错误
until other people started making the same mistake.
让我想起了大学做泊车小弟的那会
It reminded me of a college job I had parking cars.
有一天 我去泊一辆阿斯顿·马丁时
One day, I had to park an Aston Martin.
我永远也忘不了我开着那台好车时
I'll never forget the looks I got
别人投过来的羡慕眼光
driving that baby down the block.
这一次 我也一样要顺水推舟
I wasn't gonna dent this one.
我们顺便去那个鞋店看看
Hey, uh, w-what would you think
怎么样啊
about swinging by the shoe store?
好啊 去吧
Okay, let's go.
我还是不能相信刚才开过来的一路上
I still can't believe all the looks we got
那些人的眼神
driving over here.
可是你还是一直不摘掉这帽子啊
And yet you wore the hat the whole time.
你觉得我们是不是应该
Don't you think we should
把车停到靠近下个街区去啊
park on the next block over?
这附近的位子都需要停车许可证
'cause this is all permit parking.
我们以前住在这里 没事的
No, We used to live here. It's fine.
我知道 但是还是
Yeah, still. I...
好像没人在家
I don't think anybody's home.
拿着 拿好了
Here. Hang on to this.
等等 你要做什么
What -- wait, where are you going?
去后院 我们速度拍完这照片
The backyard. We'll take this picture really quickly,
然后立马闪人
and then we'll just get out of here.
不要吧 就等他们回家嘛
No, let's just -- let's just wait for them to come home.
行了 你 你这是擅闯民宅啊
Okay, that -- that's trespassing!
不 不是的 我们以前住在这里
No, it's not. We used to live here.
那也不代表我们有自便的权利啊
I don't think that does what you think it does.
就知道你没胆
Of course you would baby out,
就跟你当年不敢跳进别人家游泳池玩水一样
because this is just like pool-hopping all over again.
我 我真不觉得那有什么好玩的嘛
I just -- I don't see what was fun about that.
别家池中把水戏 自家池中无刺激
It made going in grandma's pool less special.
你的生活中还真是处处充满"刺基"啊
Why don't you try being a little less special?
会不会很高啊
Is it far?
你好
Hello.
你好 我是狗狗美容院的珊朵拉
Hi, it's Sandra from the dog groomer.
我想找歌洛莉亚
I'm trying to reach Gloria.
斯黛拉已经美容好了
Stella's ready.
我拿了她电话
Oh, I must have her phone.
她大概又拿错我的电话了
She probably grabbed mine again.
听着 我是她丈夫
Listen, this is her husband.
你那儿估计也有我的电话
You have my number right there, probably.
-打那个电话 -好的 谢谢
- Give that a call. - Okay, thanks.
你好 还是我 我马上过去
Yeah, it's me again. I'll be right there.
我的确是无故把责任归咎给她了
Yeah I did blame her for no reason.
你意见很多 说话很冲嘛 你知道吗
You have a little bit of an attitude. You know that?
我年轻的时候 是谁做洗狗这种工作呢
You know who did your job in my day?
水管
A hose.
好了 左边一点 你的左边
Okay, a little to your left, a little to your left.
对的 行了 就那儿 行了行了
Yes, okay. Right there. That's it. That's it.
很好
Perfect. Okay.
我得快点
And now I must run.
来 好了 快点
Here, okay. Fast.
准备就绪
Here we go.
重回故居感觉有点奇怪 你不觉得吗
It's weird being back here, isn't it?
是啊 所有的东西都没变
I know. Everything looks exactly the same.
是啊 就除了多了栅栏
Well, you know, except for the fence.
是啊 要那做什么啊
Yeah, what's with that?
-他们是要关什么人吗 -就是啊
- Who are they trying to keep out, anyway? - I know.
天呐 天呐
Oh. Oh, God. Oh, God.
-天呐 -哇 天呐
- Oh, God. - Oh, wow. Oh, my God.
没事 也许它很友善
No, it's okay. He might be friendly.
-它看上去很友善啊 -很友善
- He looks nice. - He looks nice.
你好啊
Hi.
天呐 不要啊 他...他好快
No! Oh, god! He's -- quickly, quickly.
不乖 一点也不乖
Not nice. So not nice.
快快快
Hurry! Hurry, hurry, hurry!
天呐 天呐
Oh! Oh! Oh, go oh, god!
现在怎么办
Now what do we do?
可以试试和它讲情 说我们以前住在这里
Well, you could try telling him we used to live here.
估计一时半会他们不会回家
They are not coming home.
我们得打电话求救啊
We need to call someone.
用你的电话吧
Use your phone.
我的电话在下面被舔的要得狂犬病了
Mine's down there getting rabies on it.
我把电话留你车子里了
No, I left mine in your car.
-什么 -我不想破坏裤子线条嘛
- What? - I didn't want to ruin the line of my pants.
天啊
Oh, God.
快看 有人来了
Oh, look. Somebody's coming.
不 看吧
No. Okay, that is what happens
让你没停车证还停那位子
when you park without a permit.
停 那是我们的车
Stop! That's ours!
我们在这上面呢 快停下
We're up here! Stop!
他无视我
He ignored me.
水手在树上基情尖叫 他怎么可以不停下
He didn't stop for the screaming sailor in a tree?
鞋子借我一用
Give me your shoe.
怎么 你以为下面那只灰太狼
What, you think that wolf down there
还会怕鞋袭吗
is gonna be afraid of a shoe?
不 没打算
No. No, I don't.
你拿老爸的酒干什么
Wh-- what are you doing with dad's wine?
小酌一杯 潇洒一回
Getting comfortable.
咱们可能要在这里长期作战呢
We could be here for a really long time.
好家伙 你怎么学会这样开瓶的
Whoa! Where'd you learn how to do that?
你又是从哪弄到的现成水手服呢
Where'd you get a sailor suit on short notice?
-算你狠 -还用说
- Fair enough. - Mm-hmm.
好恶心 是梅乐酒
Ew. It's Merlot.
你好
Hello.
曼尼
Manny!
塔拉这边怎样了
Hey, how'd it go with Tara?
还在进行中
It's still going on.
抛接球还算顺利... 基本上啦
The catch part went fine... mostly.
我一个飞扑 摔了一身泥
I took a running dive into the dirt.
那你有接到球吧
Oh, well, did you at least catch the ball?
我是扔球的时候摔倒的
I was trying to throw the ball!
我在她家浴室里找创可贴呢
I'm in her bathroom looking for band-aids.
我想鼓起勇气向她表白 正酝酿情绪呢
I'm trying to get up the nerve to tell her how I feel.
实话实说就好
Well, just be honest.
面对她 我压力很大啊
She intimidates me.
对她每开一次口 就犯一次二
Every time I open my mouth, I say something stupid.
我还夸她的卧室很"口爱"呢
I called her bedroom "fantazing."
这压根就不算个词
That's not even a word!
你在里面还好吗 曼尼
Are you okay in there, Manny?
没事 我放水洗手呢
Yeah! I'm just water-washing my hands!
救命啊 告诉我怎么说吧
Help me! Tell me what to say.
你听这样行不行
Okay, how about this...
你是六年级里 最美丽 最聪明
You are the prettiest, smartest, funniest girl
最风趣的女生
in the sixth grade.
我知道你只有十一岁
I know you're only 11,
但我无法抑制对你的想念
but I can't stop thinking about you.
我喜欢和你网聊的日子
I've loved talking to you online.
我觉得 我们应该做男女朋友
I think we should become boyfriend and girlfriend.
不不 你们想多了
No, it's not what you think.
我在跟一小男孩说话呢
I'm talking to a little boy.
越描越黑
Oh.
喂
Hello.
她没跟我在一起 小卡 我拿了她电话
She's not with me, Cam. I got her phone.
你哭什么呢
Why are you crying?
怎么会被从面包店里轰出来了
How do you get kicked out of a bakery?
这就不奇怪了
Well, that'll do it.
很抱歉要你自己来买生日蛋糕
I sorry to ask you to get your own birthday cake,
但我实在联系不到别人了
but I can't get ahold of any-- anyone else.
爱莫能助 我正要去湖边呢
Can't do it. I'm on my way to the lake...
终于
Finally.
随便在杂货店买一个吧
Just get something at the grocery store.
我不能让你吃杂货店的蛋糕
I am not getting you a grocery-store cake.
歌洛莉亚让我全权负责
Gloria asked me to handle this.
出岔子的话 我会被她念死的
She's gonna yell at me, Jay.
她说西班牙语时可毒了
she can be mean in Spanish!
行 就这样吧 大小姐
Okay, fine. Let's wrap this up, princess.
爱死你了 再见
Okay. Love you. Bye.
你们在干什么
What are you guys doing?
在剪辑给外公的生日礼物
Just editing our birthday tribute to grandpa.
但是吧 有些采访片段
You know, some of the interviews I did
效果不尽如人意
didn't turn out so well.
没事的 咱们只取其精华
That's okay. We'll just use the best stuff
充分利用手头资料
from what we all got.
好的 海莉 有什么对外公说的
Okay, Haley, talk about grandpa.
太恶了吧
Eww.
我现在穿这样 聊外公也太怪了吧
I can't talk about grandpa dressed like this.
永远爱我...
I love my --
隔壁那狗讨厌死了
That stupid dog next door!
杰 杰
Jay! Jay!
杰
Jay!!
三 四 五
...Three, four, five.
-米奇舅舅 你觉得 -一 二
Hey, uncle Mitch, what do you think -- - One, two --
-你干什么呢 -没干什么
- What are you doing? - N-nothing.
非礼勿视 非礼勿言
You didn't see this, and w-we don't tell Cam.
明白吗
Capisce?
就一分钟的事
It'lonly take one minute.
我一分钟也耽搁不起
We don't have a minute.
克莱夫·比克斯比谁呀
Who's Clive Bixby?
你妈妈的一个朋友
A friend of your mom's.
给我改天再坏
Not now!
小卡叔叔 你能不能说几句
Hey, uncle Cam, can you to talk about --
对杰说几句是吧 没时间
Jay. I know. No time.
我还要去挽救小姑娘的生日派对呢
I got a little girl's birthday party to save.
出去出去
Let's get out. Go.
现在不行 宝贝
Oh, not now, honey.
你爸刚回来 去问他吧
Your father's out back. Why don't you call him?
菲尔
Phil!
当爹的 孩子需要你啊
Dad! Your kids need you!
外公真的很酷
Grandpa is really cool.
他还曾让我喝他的啤酒
He once let me drink some of his beer.
我
for the love of --
沙士啤酒[不含酒精]
Root beer!
我发誓我们不只这些视频吧
I could've sworn we had more!
让我施展我的魔法吧
Well, let me work my magic.
只要来点创意的编辑就好
It's all about creative editing.
只要给我两个小时
Just give me two hours
然后再加一小时
and another hour.
谁给我去拿杯巧克力牛奶
Somebody get me some chocolate milk
盐多放点
with extra salt.
还记得当初你退出童子军时
Do you remember the time you quit cub scouts
老爸对你发火 然后你就跑到这上面来么
and dad got mad at you so you ran away up here?
记得 你把晚餐送到这来给我吃
Right. And you brought me my dinner up here...
-还有我的漫画书 -没错
- ...and my comic books. - Yep.
当年要不是你还跑回家里上厕所
I think mom and dad would have been a lot more scared
老爸老妈可能真的会吓坏
if you hadn't been running into the house to use the bathroom.
我不能在外面尿尿
I can't go outside.
拜你所赐 现在我想尿尿了
Great, now I'm thinking about it.
米奇尔
Mitchell...
这太讽刺了
it's ironic.
我们一直想要在这院子里养条狗
We always wanted a dog in this backyard,
但我们从未养过一条
and we could never have one.
曼尼却养了一条
Y-- Manny got one.
曼尼要什么有什么
Mm. Manny gets everything.
没错
Yeah.
你认为曼尼会得到三分之一的...
Hey, you think Manny's gonna get a third of...
三分之一的什么
A third of what?
你懂的
You know.
我猜会吧
Uh...I guess.
当然 他得到也不为过啊[杰的遗产]
Sure. I mean, that seems fair.
对吧 是吗
Right? Does it?
-克莱尔 是吗 因为我刚觉得 -够了
- Claire, does it? 'cause I just feel like -- - Okay?
我想我们喝高了
You know what? I think we've probably had enough of this.
好的 等等
Okay, wait.
如果我们让这条狗去追赶这个娃娃
Do you think if we could get the dog to chase this doll,
我们就能迅速跑下去捡起手机了吧
then we could run down and grab the phone really quick?
-好办法 -是的
- We could do that! - Yeah.
我们只要扔的远远的就好
We just are gonna have to throw it really, really far.
没错 所以
Right. So...
朝那边扔
That way. Mm-hmm.
歌洛莉亚 我还想去那家的鞋店逛逛
Gloria, um, I'd still love to swing by that shoe store.
如果你急着去的话 你就自己去吧
If you're in a hurry, go by yourself.
不 我等你一起 惠普尔
No. I'll wait. Whipple!
惠普尔
Whipple!
好了
Okay! Mm!
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
完美极了 转过来看看另一边
Oh, it's perfect. Uh, l-let's see the other side.
惠普尔
Whipple!
-咳嗽了 还好吧 -没事
- Bless you. - Thank you.
有点太紧了 不是吗
It's a little too tight, no?
-你觉得臀部好看么 -我觉得棒极了
- What do you think of the tush? - Oh, I think it's great.
你何不这么保持几秒钟呢
Why don't you keep it right there for a second.
可以看仔细点
Let's make sure.
好的 但是这有点透
Yeah, but it's a little see-through.
或许把这个穿在下面 就不会那么露了
Maybe if I put this underneath, then it won't, like, show.
不不不 这样看起来棒极了
No, no, no, no, no. It looks good that way.
-我去试试看有没更好的 -不 等等
- I go try something else better. - No, wait!
等等
Wait!
别犹豫了 你想穿就买啊
Oh, don't think about it. Just get it.
真搞笑 惠普尔 我在陪人逛呢
Hilarious, Whipple. I'm actually here with someone.
你的"美女无踪"魔术终于成功了
And you finally did make something disappear.
-几秒钟前她还在这呢 -谁不信你啊
- She was here a second ago. - Of course she was.
就跟当年你说要带个美女来舞会
Just like the date you had on the final-night dance
结果却不见人影一个样
of junior tumbling congress.
那是因为堵车
There was traffic.
当然
Sure.
我认为我找到了
I think I found something
一件可以让我老公很高兴的衣服
that is going to make my husband very happy.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
老公觉得非常高兴 歌洛莉亚
Oh, very happy, Gloria.
十分高兴
Very happy.
好的 不要走远了
Okay, but don't go far away
等会我可能需要你帮忙我拉拉链 好吗
because I might need help with the zipper, okay?
好呀 拉拉链
Sounds good... with the zipper.
菲尔
Wow. Phil.
那是你老婆吗
I mean, wow. That's your wife?
看来的确如此
It would appear so.
很高兴见到你 格伦
Great to see you, Glen.
我得说 我有点小惊讶
You know, I got to say, I'm a little surprised.
惊讶
Surprised...
还是困惑了呢
or mystified?
靠 掉你的衣服里了
Damn it. It went down your shirt.
你自个儿留着吧
You can...keep it.
-后会有期 -不不 我只是一直以为
- I'll see ya. - No, no. I just always assumed
你会和克莱尔·普里契特结婚呢
you would marry Claire Pritchett.
你记得克莱尔
You remember Claire?
废话 她可是美若天仙啊
Are you kidding? She was gorgeous.
老天 当年我多羡慕嫉妒恨啊
God, I was so jealous of you back then.
当年你对我羡慕嫉妒恨啊
You were jealous of me?
那是啊 兄弟
Oh, man.
金发飘飘的克莱尔·普里契特
Claire Pritchett with the blond hair
她那柳叶弯眉 迷人微笑
and those browes, great smile.
她的一颦一笑至今依旧清晰如画
Oh, I can picture her smiling right now.
我想象不出
I can't.
是谁得到了她的"最终开垦权"啊
I wonder who landed her.
真他娘的有福
Lucky son of a bitch.
是啊
Yeah.
菲尔 我需要你
Phil, I need you!
又要干嘛啦
What now?!
对不起
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
我一会就来
I'll be there in a second.
哇靠 咋不见的
No! How?!
你们到底在想什么
What the hell were you thinking?
我帮你们回答 你们没想过
I'll answer that for you. You weren't thinking.
你觉得那很有趣吗 大力水手
You think that's funny, popeye?
-不 -大力水手
- No. - Popeye.
我现在应该是在钓鱼
I should be fishing,
但我却得大老远的穿过半个城市
but I'm hauling my ass across town
从只小狗嘴下救你们两个二货
trying to save you two from a little dog.
至少那一小段时间里 我们有狗
At least we got to have a dog for a few minutes.
又来了
There we go.
你至少可以表示一下感谢吧
You could show a little gratitude, you know.
这裤子可是新的呢
These pants are new.
爬围墙时很可能会弄破
Climbing over that fence, I might have wrecked 'em.
真成熟
That's mature.
-对不起 -真对不起
- I'm sorry. - We're sorry. I'm so-- we're sorry.
对不起 以为你说的是 直肠
I'm sorry you said "rectum."
老爸 我错了
I'm sorry, dad.
-很感激你可以来救我们 -谢谢
- Um, we're so glad that you came and got us. - Thank you.
你把狗引开的办法真是太绝了
It was very smart the way that you distracted the dog.
我一年就只能买十二次月度香肠
12 times a year, I get sausages.
五月的 就这么没了
That's it.
六月香肠出来前 我毛都没的吃了
What the hell am I gonna to do till June?
看看
Let's see it.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
只要备好生日蜡烛就行了
We just need some candles.
肯定都收在某个抽屉里了
I must have in one of the drawers.
好吧
Okay.
果脆圈 项链
Froot loop necklace...
圣婴
Baby Jesus...
钥匙 这钥匙找好久了
Keys. Ay, I was looking for these keys.
圣婴
Baby Jesus...
气枪
B.B. Gun...
又是圣婴
More baby jesus...
还是圣婴
Ay, another baby --
天呐 斯黛拉 不要
Jesus, Stella! Don't do that!
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
杰 你不能进来
No, Jay! Don't come in here!
你不能先看到蛋糕
You cannot see the cake!
会带来霉运
It's the bad luck!
我早就看过了
I already saw the cake.
是我买的 我没去钓鱼
I bought it while I was busy not fishing.
不 去酒吧那边 去
No. Go out to the bar. Go!
在没养那只笨狗之前
You never used to talk to me like that
你从不会这么对我说话
before we got that damn dog.
曼尼 我差点就要打电话给你了
Hey, Manny. I almost called you.
你和塔拉进展如何
How'd it go with Tara?
我觉得 一般般吧
Okay, I guess.
我用了你教我的台词 的确很管用
I used every line you gave me, and she totally ate it up.
那为什么只是一般般啊
Oh. Well, then, why just okay?
她是约我下次去棒球练习场
She wants to go on a date now...
再续前缘呢
to the batting cage.
打棒球也不太行吗
Not so good with a bat?
是啊 除非是让我用球棒来擀面
I am, as long as I'm using it to roll out dough.
你只是需要练习练习就行了
I'll bet you just need a little practice.
我在你这么大岁数时
You know, when I was your age,
用球棒打气球都打不到
I couldn't hit a balloon with a bat.
后来我爸爸带我去实地练习
Then my father took me out to the field,
几个小时之后
and a couple hours later,
我都能打全垒打了
I was knocking the hide off that ball.
那是我与老爸最开心的日子之一
It's one of the best days we ever had together.
真的吗
Really?
是的
Yeah.
你只是需要花时间练习
I just bet you need some time in a batting cage.
你这个周末有什么计划
What are you doing this weekend?
-会很好玩的 -这个主意好
- That'd be fun, huh? - That's a great idea!
我问下杰 他喜欢做这些事情
I'll ask Jay. He loves stuff like this.
那恭喜你们父子俩啊
That'll be great for you guys.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢你今天的帮忙 小卡
And thanks for your help today, Cam.
不客气
You got it.
我不觉得外公今天玩的开心
I don't think grandpa's having the best time.
他一直在给自己倒酒
He keeps going and getting more drinks.
不是每次都在倒酒
Well, not every time.
有一次他是去查看女篮比赛的得分
One time he went in to check on the women's basketball score.
要是有人想知道的话 火花队领先八分
The sparks are up by 8, if anyone cares.
好吧 老爸 我们都得跟你道歉
Okay, dad, we all owe you an apology.
我们一直想要给你一个美好的晚上
We were so worried about giving you a great night
却破坏了你自己的安排
that we ruined your day,
真的很抱歉 害你没能去钓鱼
and I'm really sorry we didn't let you go fishing.
-对不起 爸爸 -对不起 杰
- Sorry, dad. - Sorry, Jay.
对不起 对不起 外公
Sorry. Sorry, grandpa. Sorry.
其实呢 我也是个混蛋
You know what? I'm acting like a jerk.
我又不是十二岁
What am I, 12?
不就不能钓鱼吗 我用得着撅嘴生气吗
So I didn't get to go fishing. What, am I gonna pout about it?
我有我的家人 你们为我做了这么多
I still have my family, and you guys made such a big fuss.
我爱你们
I love you all.
我们去吃蛋糕 拆礼物吧
So let's go get some cake and presents.
好
Yes!
蛋糕和礼物 大家来吧
Cake and presents! Come on, everybody!
-宝贝 -怎么了
- Honey? - Yeah?
我告诉过你 拥有你我是如此幸运吗
Have I told you how lucky I am to have you?
歌洛莉亚 借过
Gloria, excuse me.
我发自内心这么认为
'Cause I am.
好吧
Okay.
-祝你... -不要唱歌
- Hap-- ? - No singing.
这蛋糕怎么变成这样了
What the hell happened to the cake?
没有啊 挺漂亮的啊
Nothing. It's beautiful.
好了 咱们来拆礼物吧
Okay, let's open the presents.
没错 礼物礼物 礼物礼物
Yes! Presents! Presents! Presents! Presents!
-先拆谁的 -我先来 先拆我的
- Who's first? - Mine first. Mine first.
您知道的 克莱尔跟我--
And as you know, Claire and I--
我们的礼物还没完成
we didn't quite finish ours,
不过我们会尽速做好给您补上的
but we will be getting that to you.
好的
Fine.
我们的礼物本来是满瓶的红酒和一张生日卡
And our gift is a fuller version of that and a card.
很好
Wonderful.
当然了 这个蛋糕 是...是我的
And, of course, the cake is, uh, mine.
真不错
Fantastic.
然后这里还有一个
And here we have a phone...
嘴唇形状的电话
in the shape of a mouth.
不用谢啦 很性感吧
Ah, you're welcome! Very sexy!
先等一下 别提示我
Oh, wait a minute. Don't tell me.
让我自己把这个搞搞清楚
Let me work this out.
我曾经提过几次说我想要一个萨克斯风
I mentioned a few times that I was thinking of taking up the saxophone,
结果你送了我一个这样的电话
and you give me this.
我懂了 这是个性感电话是吧
I got it! Is this a sexy phone?!
生日快乐
Happy birthday!!
好了 还有什么别的吗
All right, what else we got?
那个...没有了
Oh, uh...n-nothing.
也许这个家里的大人们
Hmm. Maybe not a perfect showing
表现得有些差强人意
on behalf of the adults in the family,
但是别忘了 孩子们还准备了礼物呢
but don't forget the kids still have their big gift.
而且做这个礼物花了我们一年时间呢
And it took us a year to make.
礼物就在影碟机里
It's in the DVD player.
你们一定得过来看看
You've got to come watch it.
好的
Okay.
我好兴奋哦 咱们快去 杰
I'm so excited! Let's go, jay!
我来拿着你的性感电话
I bring your sexy phone.
是啊 可别忘了
Oh, don't forget that.
所以某种意义上讲也算是我们大家的礼物
so this is kind of from all of us.
没错 关灯吧
Yeah. Hit the lights!
-爸爸 -杰
-Dad! -Jay!
杰
Jay!!
-外公 -我们
-Grandpa... -We...
-爱 -你[与恶心发音相同]
-Love... -Eww!
明白吗
Capisce?
谁想再看一遍
Well, who wants to see it again?
这就完了 你就用了这么点镜头吗
That's it? That's all you used?
我连一个镜头都没有
I wasn't even in it!
那可真够烂的
That totally sucked.
你们知道吗 派对很棒
You know what? Great party.
谢谢你们都能来
Thank you all for coming.
我希望你们能原谅我 我要上楼去
And I hope you forgive me -- I'm gonna go upstairs,
躺着看会儿小说 然后就睡觉了
Curl up with a Ludlum, and call it a day.
喂
Hello.
曼尼
Manny?
你在哪里
Where are you?
你在那儿干什么
What are you doing out there?
你干嘛呢
What the hell?
我今天下午把它拖到这儿来的
I dragged it back here this afternoon.
我知道这并不是个湖
I know it's not the lake,
可我们还是可以边喝饮料
but maybe we could pop open a few drinks
边在上面享受会人生嘛
and hang out on the water?
以前的杰会回答
Now, the old Jay would have said,
"我是想坐在湖面上与鱼竿和阳光为伴
"I wanted to be on a lake with a fishing rod and sunshine,
而不是大半夜坐在游泳池里起伏荡漾"
not bobbing around at night in a swimming pool."
我还是怀念以前的杰
I miss the old Jay.
梦想中的生活 不过如此 对吧
This is the life, huh?
的确是还不错
It ain't half bad.
我也想上船去
Ay, I want to get in the boat!
-船长 你说呢 -好吧
- Captain? - All right.
我也要去 我也要上去
Me too! I want to get in!
来吧 咱们上船
Come on, let's get in.
你今天跟克莱尔过得怎么样
So, how was your day with Claire?
你知道吗 其实 其实很不错
You know, it was actually -- it was really great.
虽然我不 我不常想这些事情
I don't -- I don't always think about it,
但我很庆幸长大的路上有她的陪伴
but I-I was really lucky to have her to grow up with.
我根本无法想象
You know, I cannot imagine
独自大战我那对疯癫爸妈的情景
dealing with my crazy parents alone.
是啊
Yeah.
小卡
Cam?
什么事
Hmm?
我 我还想再要一个孩子
I -- I want to have another baby.
你觉得这次要个男孩怎么样
What would you think about a boy this time?
好了 小心
All right, easy.
-小心 小心点 船都摇晃了 -不 不 不
- Easy! Easy! You're rocking the boat! - No, no, no!
我抓住克莱尔了 我抓住克莱尔了
I got Claire! I got Claire!
好了 啊嘿[水手打招呼语]
All right, ahoy!
这么说 如果我们都...
So, if we all just, uh...
好了 所有人都上楼去
Ok. Everybody upstairs.
卢克 你立刻去洗个热水澡
And, Luke, I want you to get in a hot bath right away.
我还在发抖呢
I'm still shivering.
这就是人们不在船上随意起立的原因
That's why you don't stand up in a boat.
我那是在扮世界之王呢[泰坦尼克号]
I was king of the world.
现在你成了暗夜之傻了
Well, now you're dork of the night.
亲爱的...
Honey...
我有没有告诉过你我有多幸运
Have I told you how lucky I am?
你是说从晚饭时开始吗
You mean since dinner?
我实在忍不住这么想
I can't help it --
你美丽的眼眸 如丝的秀发
Your beautiful eyes, your silky hair.
答应我你永远不会...
Promise me you'll never...
改变
change.
我不得不承认 这招还挺撩人呢
I have to admit, that's kind of hot.
或许我该去"改变"一下装扮
Maybe I will go change.
哥始终还是哄妞界一霸啊
I still got it.
消停会儿吧你
Knock it off!